Good morning everyone it's friday at nine am that they
after the build...so many things you all for being early birds here today
this bing builds with bing please be very welcome im
...for title I am that product lead for being api...and I'm here today with
...wherein with the product lead for being webmaster
experiences and our goal today is only one we
want you to make awesome apps and we believe you can do
...by leveraging api isn't tools that being provides so that you can maker
...much more discoverable and make
then richer as well now you might rightfully sk
...can...tell me what credentials being has really to make my
...awesome you might say I won't be able to answer your evaluation surveyed in
of the session unless you really can convince me really what are the credentials...being has to make
corrects awesome well my answer to that is quite brief actually being has increasingly
become the intelligence engine behind many solutions in the industry
some of those solutions are actually microsoft products themselves so whenever you use
...turner office windows xbox you are
using bing somehow being helps to provide some immersive experience is to those products at some point
however been also evolved to our...solutions in the industry,
for example, sweeter four-square amazon and
...hope today to open up a little bit more of...so that you all...can
in richer apps engage and reach millions of people.
We believe that goals really hand-in-hand with the fact that
...five times more engage and
...the browser alone and we want to leverage the opportunity to explore
that opportunity through to fronts vincent
will tell you how to bring users more often to your
...and how to bring more users to your app of course is going to talk about some
really cool technologies related to epics...free and that...or
mayans I'll tell you once you have your users on your...how you can keep
them engaged I'm going to talk about some data and resources that being provides,
for example, use images videos and hopefully
you can complement that data with order being powered solutions and data...well you're seeing...build,
for example, maps...and orders as well to really create your all
...map so that's our plan so basically...briefly go through the being that
...then...going to explore the being search api in a little bit of more details
...a bunch of demos then vincent will take on explain epics...that
linking and finally go to our final conclusions so let's briefly start with bing
...if there's only one link you should remember from this talk please make that to be
bev but being dot com let me switch to my machine here for one second?
The...so that center is your first
is stop shop for you to know everything about the public being api and tools.
You might have seen lots of the technologies with display here been presented at build again,
for example, maps speech perhaps
ads today like us to talk a little bit more about
the search api so this search api...concepts sounds quite simple
...it is an api that enables you to search
...like you to really see the search api
as the window through which are at can bring the world's data so...users,
for example, the most recent news about a given topic or
the most relevant images about a given text or perhaps you want to just read
millions of websites or...results and do something with those
...explains you first a couple things your?
Which is?
Through the being search api you have to main scenarios
...can either embed the search results in our app or you can programmatic
...consume and do something with them and no payment is required for
...start using the api is there's a limit of five thousand calls or
transactions per month you can perform and that's for free so we can just get started today
to a couple cliques get a key and start consuming to being search api now before we get into our first them
all let-me highlights to flavors of the search api that we
have available here you can see the left we have the full-fledged?
Bing api and that one has seven endpoints you can
consume each one of the first six endpoints individually get results,
for example,
web page results or image results video results news results related
searches results and finally spell correction results as well by calling those individual
endpoints you can also called...composite endpoint...to get multiple sourced
...or multiple types of results through a single call if
your scenario however is more simple like perhaps
...just really wants to have web results in my app you can also called the
being search api the web only version so through that you can actually have
I smaller payload and also the transaction costs of that one is cheaper
for you so let me go back here and see how we can explore
the search api so once I click here in the search api you'll see
...redirected to the microsoft leisure marketplace that's where the...regulates
that's where you go to back to get the being search api data then as I mentioned to
you five thousand transactions per month so you can get started for free slightly click here in sign-in.
And, I do have a best account can use for this.
That would be a horrible time for me to forget my passwords.
And, apparently did...it is builds twenty fifteen demo.
That looks better now and one of the first things you can do after you sign up for the
being search api
...to actually explored the api through a kind of api consul you
see a link here explore this dataset let's click there and then have a small api consul
that can play around to get life data from the api so in this case
year let's assume I want to do a query and I want to search for
...and...can specifying this sources parameter what are the source
...the result types I want to get back well in this case let's...and use back from
ming plus web results and perhaps some video results as well you
click and apply?
And, here you have some of information coming back to you live from the api
that's a total number of web results of the results so on and
you can expand here one of those results perhaps news.
Now you can...coming...from being in can our your app with that kind of
data lots of people like to use the api explorer so that they can see
have an idea of the data that comes back from the api I myself like to use this
to also explore the endpoints that I have available and what
are the response fields or pretty much my api schema for each one of those
endpoints that helps me to get more familiarized with the api now let's look...here,
you know, it is...in the morning perhaps you guys have enough coffee let me show to
you how you can actually consume data from the being search api with
zero coding required all of the being api...see here are actually all
data restful api is so that means if you have a tool that understands all data like,
for example, xcel our...can just
pull that data and displaying your solution so this is what I want to try to do
here but just show you a quick screenshot of what I want to achieve so right now I
have the like to do something like this imagine that you want just to create the list of
san-francisco bars or something else with like images titles and links
or perhaps list of articles and news articles about morocco...you do not need to create
...from scratch for doing something like that you can leverage already
other tools that just hook into the being search api to collect some data so let's say
a couple steps how we can do that but moved back here to my machine?
So, let me start by opening xcel.
Then you can check this our...to add here in the rhythm and then you can click
...manage to manager data you can pull some data now into excel now you can
...like to get some external data from the windows
leisure marketplace again that's where the being search api...slightly click here.
Now it's not tell you okay which data from the edge marketplace
...you want to add here to xcel in my case that's data comes from the being search api.
It might ask me to sign again...just...really quickly.
And, after that's complete you'll see and interface really similar to the api explore
we're just checking awhile ago and in this case let's do this
...search for images and I'm looking now for
...recipes so let's try that.
Let me click and apply.
You will see again data coming back from the being api that looks good this time now when I click
...select query.
Xcel is imports in the data from the being api into our
...and then you'll see how we can use our view to make some...visualization off
that data so typically takes a couple seconds I believe very important right now one thousand
...coming from the being api and I'm going to show you how your users can also
refresher data to get most updated content...so shouldn't take long just a couple more seconds.
Assuming the internet cooperates of course the regal.
So, that's perfect our...populated with data coming from the being api now let me just get
back to my original excel spreadsheet right here and then I can goal to
insert menu they can select our view and then the data I got back from the
being search api will be available in the spain right here in the right side for me
to start selecting what fields I want to...report
so let's see here the media url those are all...the fields that the arbitrarily
the api response so let me select here perhaps the media url that's the actual image.
In the indeed responses so I can clicking enable content and here in my images will be loading
a secondary goal...psyched here d title of those images and
let-me select here perhaps the source url for people to click.
Okay, that sounds good I have some nice breeder recipes right here then I
...in the...I can off-course perhaps weed out some results
...can do some filtering here if I want that's not the case right now so I can just have a name.
For my reports.
And, then as you can see here this is a regular excel spreadsheet right so you can
save that file...someone else that personal can click
...refresh and get most recent results so that's it
with zero coding you are able now to just pull some data from
the being search api and I'll have that added to your app now let's assume you want to do something else
and you said okay that's great now I just want really to code.
...for you to code you need to do two things first ensure you get your account
key from the bing search api page...the microsoft...marketplace and
off-course register your application...being measure marketplace so that you can start authenticate
...europe so let's do that what I want to do right now you have a really simple
...api world demo I want to be able to quickly programmatic
...search for web results using a command prompt
...so let's go back to my machine.
And, if I go to...being search api page
...like to show you two things folks so the first one is if you click on my account.
Right here in the account case you can find some keys you can use already to do some
...really quick development and start pulling being api data search api data into your
...you can create additional keys if you want perhaps one for each
app and this will enable you to do some basic
off bypassing that key both is the user name and password you can read start collecting some data
mac of course in the real-world you might you really willing to do something more
...you guys might have heard about off in order authentication
mechanisms so to use something like that you can click...the developer stab.
Then you can register replication really similar process
...creating perhaps like a facebook app or twitter app you register your at first you provide a
klein's id for that...the name for your app perhaps to provide a...secret which is the
...now you can use o off providing that information there and then you can
have more kind of...boost sign up in my case here I'll just stick with the account
case because as a simple mechanism for you for us...quick...the second thing I want to show you
is this if you actually check in the search api page in the right it's
not tell you there is a dot net csharp less library that you can consume
that is a really easy way for you to start retrieving programmatic...being a data from the
being search api I already have a solution here in...you that's a simple
command from solution already downloaded that file right here that's my being search container
class and let me just do this let me quickly now perhaps tell the user
answer your query.
And, then...course read.
Whatever the user entered.
All right and final step I'm going to show the results from
being best in the query is a parameter.
So, that's live demo here right now let's hope that works.
For me to...
small proxy class library that I downloaded from the being search api
...page just a quick note that you have to other reference to system dot data
...services of...
then I need to three simple things first one I have mikey the same one-l showing to
use seconds ago second step instantiate that
proxy class which is the being search container it receives as a parameter by
uri in this case that's the being search api
...api data market...dot com...beings lash search.
Now you set the credentials of that proxy class-based...your key as the by as...mentioned
...the password and finally now
...proxy class has some methods that you can use to
create web queries or image queries video queries so on right here I'm creating
a web query and of course you have all those other methods video to
create a video query and then the composite method as well which will
enable you to have multiple sourced types being returned with only one single
call explored is...upcoming them so I have my web query right here now I just need to
execute query now and iterated over
the results displaying title and display url really simple just a couple lines of code cannot
programmatic consume data from the being search api
...customized way so let's give this a try so my queries going to be perhaps xbox.
...I'm getting some results back from the being search api.
That's great of course...a bunch of parameters that you can explore I'm going to touch them in a while.
So, that's good now we have a really simple hello world application what else can we do with the being api
what order more interesting scenarios we can just light up using the being search api
...let's imagine we are developing a modern app that
is called shared lists the idea of this app is that
...more people can actually start collecting and
...even websites and use images of a given topic that
...exploring together so in this case here
imaginative incense and I would like to save some interesting things refining here at the
...going to explore we're going to create and app powered by being...enables us to achieve that
scenario in this case I'm actually going to show you how you can use more modern technologies for
you to
get negate...data like the web api http client classes doing a
...calls and then I want to tell you how you can actually choose between serialized...they do get back
from being either through data contracts or actually just doing some dynamics realization is really up
to you depending on your scenario so let's explore that let me go back to my machine.
There you go and I have a second solution right here shared
lists pretty much empties with some just a couple of event handlers right here.
And, that's my main page main page has just some,
you know,...why controls but that's indian and empty
...has no data let's see how we can hook some being data into that specific...
So, one of the things I want to highlight you first is as I mentioned all of the being api
art restful all data feeds so if you go to a tool like post
...and just call here to being api using a
really regular simple http get call that's it you get some
...on data back in this specific case I'm actually calling the web
endpoints and I'm actually...my query xbox as the parameter
the percentage twenty-seven is just for me to escape the quote that's required for all
string parameters and...you can see here baller format equals js and gives me some
js and data back so if you want perhaps to embed that data into your ios
...right and that's possible as well right now let's just do this calling
using modern app it windows store...in csharp so first that
let me initially actually have define...url that I want to build
so in this case here I'm calling the composite endpoint
...to-you and the composite endpoint has a sources parameter that
tells us what is the kind of data want to get back from the being a see the being search api
have web plus...scape carter four-plus images
in use in spell corrections right then I'm
specifying my query just have a placeholder in here for now and again format equals
...so that's my query this...url actually and that's my
...now whenever the user taps in the search button let's see what's going to
happen like to show some results again this time whatever the user
had results for whatever the user had...query xbox.
Perfect you will see now I
already editor reference to the web api two-point-two clients
...using nugget so he's right here and then
...the show results let me just make this to be my query.
You will see that I can consume that data...really similar way in which I was also consuming
that through the proxy class so let me now invoke my composite
call as you can see here and just...a single modifier
...here having some...calls right now so I use
my hb client class normally the only difference here is that I'm
specifying like http client handler that sets my network credentials as I
did before now I'm calling gets method...the get a
...method that's a gets http call passing that url
in my actual queries so this should be my query actually getting receiving as a parameter
...response I'm just reading that response in this case I'm serialized
...the response into a data
...class call being search results which is right here and you might be
...mihai under how did really builds
these being search results class well there's a small trick in visual studio might
know already whenever here we have some...on data
then get is raw data if you copy that your clipboard then you go back to visual studio.
You can always.
Based that data especially mc basis special based my
...in my clipboard classes and there you go I have a data conflict less for me right here that's
...can use and that's what I did in this case.
Slice...that data they receive back from
being search api into my being search results and again the only difference now is
that and this time I'm actually just creating a list of all the objects I get back,
for example, web results image news I just put all those things together in
a single list and I bind that to my results...which is
...ui element that I having there and then have of course some code that says how the
why should be rendered according to the data it receives back?
...that looks good let's give it a try so let me run this code.
Hopefully they'll go there with me today unless search for hollow lengths.
After a couple seconds hopefully
...we have some data coming back this time I have now web results.
Images as well and some news results as well so the idea is that
now I can start click and saving those results and start building my list.
Now what is really the interesting thing we can do on top of this
might be the one of the most important slides of this presentation
right now which shows to-you that by using the being api
as you can leverage lots of things that bing dot com already has lots of
...common logic capabilities optimizations we
...bing dot com you also get that through the api
...comes with its when you are using the api...for example,...you know,
that being is global by design right if you're using
being from a different place like brazil you get results relevant to brazil not relevant
to the united states if I go back to my code right here.
You will see something quite similar ...
Let me launch my...again let me search
for games and right now you will see a have english us results
okay united states websites or at least
...relevant to the united states market if
...if the...of...takes does that over to brazil and
runs that same query there is going to get actually brazilian portuguese results that are more
relevant to them you can off-course override or have some kind of fallback behavior
through the market parameter so if I really simple modification right here let me just add the new
...markets to my url and this time pete...which is the market
called for brazil and let me just escape that again...in single quotes?
So, if I run that again and I search for the same thing, for example, games.
This design now I
get results relevant to the brazilian portuguese market not english market.
The second thing...get imagination supports of course you might not
really be willing to display all results at once so we do support counts
...parameters actually bowler top and...skip parameters that
you can use as the number of results want to get back and of course as the offset that you
want to retrieved eureka results from so in this case...me just createanother queries sorry
another url and let-me specify and bowler top.
Equals two so just want to get the first to results in here and for simplicity
let me just retrieve here web and images let's assume I do not want use and spell anymore.
Let's run it again so this time let-me search for bill gates.
And, I get only to...only to images because they specify that as a
...what also having here hits highlight
...you go to bing of calm or.
Right here you search for something like
games again and then the results you get some things which are...that hopefully
they'll we'll just make users to engage more you can get that...in...from the api as well
you specify web options equals hits highlight...the...
will give you back now some special charger can use to bold some specific relevant
terms of getting the result so that's also something that comes with the api
...parameters so eventually you might want to change the
set safe search settings author api so that
...options are strict moderate and off those are the same as an being dot com you can also
passive perimeter that changes that and sites that your app as well if that's part of your
scenario query alteration that's something really interesting so let me go back
here and run this again let me just do this I do not want the portuguese
market anymore let me just revert that and I want all the results...
So, let's imagine the user they just.
...here...probably did something stupid probably that's still comments...regal.
So, users they just
...type things all the time write as a user running feeling my forms and everything and just have a
lot lots of cycles now and then and if the user actually searches for something like
billy data set of bill gates we do not wants to
penalize that user by showing no results for bill gates which very likely was the user
intent in the first-place so when you go to being...com bing knows that and tells you
hey actually I think you are meaning bill gates let me show results for bill gates that
behavior is true for the api as well so if you search for
...it's going to show you bill gates results...can override that
behavior if you want and...be getting some...as barbecuing texas somewhere instead of the
bill gates specific results so the api supports that finally filtering
you can future api results by.
You can future web page results...
type you can see only give me back web results which are off-site pdf or
...documents you can do that...of...future perimeter perhaps you can want
to future results free specific domain you could say give me only results
for specific domain like recipes dot com are not all results of the web you can do that if
you want as well and have some order kind of filtering behaviors I want to show you what you want to do here as
...far-left demos which is?
Imagine you want to get image results however
only black-and-white image results and let's imagine that you also want to get all
those in the that all of those image results actually they have faces in them
to do that you just need to specify in your image futures
...being monochrome that provides the black-and-white behavior and the
face equals face the other possible value for faces
portrait that means the not give my faces...close-up what more
...of a porches behavior you can specify that let's give that one...right let me move back here.
And, let me just add a new url.
This time now that contains an image future.
Right here same saying the same thing you had...image...is caller monochrome
...and that's it just by having a really simple parameter you
can run that again knowledge search for something like music.
And, this time now you only get black-and-white results that contains faces so you can see
here frank sinatra you can see john lennon research for science.
You can see here albert einstein.
Carl sagan and orders that's pretty cool you can just
...some parameters to get some specific results in there
and this light has a reference lots of your results or the other filters that you can...so,
for example,
you can also future images by size aspect racial the style you
can future videos by duration aspect resolution and
news that's quite interesting you can say only give me back and use which
are business news or health news world news us new science music
and specify all of those...part of your future perimeters as well now what about this what about the
...suggestions in spell corrections and that's not against
...specific really guys this is something that you can use in any kind of you want really to suggest
users some spell corrections can you do that yes that's quite simple in my
...that I have right here.
Let me move back to my original full.
Url do not need image one anymore and here when grabbing
my results I'm just going to inspect if in the api response I get
any spell suggestions and that's it if we have more than one spell suggestion that can actually
display that to the user and I'm just right here...just enabling some
...y component in there that says hey I'm including results for this corrected
...here you really want results for this thing you just...that a try.
Let me search again for really get...in this case.
And, now you can get I spell correction right here telling you hey,
you know, I really think...something else here is a spell correction for
you and then you can define what it...trigger here perhaps you can
redo the search now specifically using that user specific germ that they provide.
All right...the sparse my less them...before...bring vincent into talk about
...discovery and...is about how
well this being api or the search api integrates with...api, for example,
the translator api in order tools and services you see actually as part of the being that
center quite easy let's imagine here that in our
...whenever I move the mouse over a given result I want to...
small translation of that result and every...result...multiple relation in there so I have some quick
coding here for the actual translation api and you'll see the way I call that api
...quite similar to the way you called the being search api the same three steps first you have
your url so in this case...the endpoint for the translator api is lashing is
lash microsoft translator then I can specify to and from parameters
...say from english for instance to spanish getting
that in...as well and then of course have to provide...retrieved from the user.
Once I have that actually retrieve what is the actual texture information I want to get that I
want to translate and then really, really similar thing you have seen before we have an http client
I just consume best my client handler with my keys and then this
time now check how interesting when I call my translator api
and I get my response I'm not serialized...data contract
class anymore what I'm doing here I'm just doing some dynamics realization and then
you can in realtime have...field structurally be inspected and that's how you're
defining the actual value for those fields let's give they want to try as well.
So, let's do here search for bill gates.
And, let's choose some...translators
have some new stuff down here let's see...gates you can help the world
...million lines let-me click here and then...my translation...is
...model solver...elastic spanish-speaking portuguese that's my the best spanish over
here for me that's it that's how you can integrate some of the translate
...functionality with the search api and hopefully you can also integrates order stuff for learn that
...maps ads speech and
...really compelling experience so I just want to
highlight you folks that indian the being api...the search api
...they're not really simply widgets that only webmasters can, you know,
move and dropped in your pages for end-users to see a translation of that page that's
really a full-fledged api that you can use for all of your scenarios
the way that you want so again I think the key thing to highlight here is that whatever you
have already in bing dot com global by design lots of the supports for
many different futures all of that spell corrections query alterations all of that is made
available to you through the api as well and again it takes just a couple cliques
...to get started in start consuming the api is there's no need
for your really to even have a credit card to start playing around and check that out so please go to
...have not been dot com explore the...api
...that I'm just going to call vince in so that he can tell you now once...have your
...who can make your at much more discoverable and have...users to come back there more often
...thank you?
Thank you...
...thanks factor come out this early morning...is amazing but,
not of android kinda...how easy it is to make
or apps that out with smarter experiences using the family of being api
...I want to switch gears a little bit and talk about you know-how we can make apps more discoverable.
I want to talk about how you can reach engagement is a peep.
I want to talk about how we at bing think about.
Making your apps more discoverable and connect them to the people and get them to hands users
bing is the key provider intelligence to windows microsoft products as
a whole and ecbatana and windows and specific want to talk about
app discover ability and we talk about app discover ability
really we talk about three things.
Especially talk about it research we need to think about how people just find
To searches for an app name or cattle research.
But,...once more natural and common way for people to search.
Is the search for content so...want to talk about content discovery apps?
finally people want to do something with your app they want to completed task
performing action so we need to talk about app action discovery as well.
When it comes to app discovery and searching for app names and cattle researches for apps the
...got you covered very well and as a developer you don't really have to do a whole other
thing other than publisher app to the store fill...the correct metadata
...that makes it accessible to the search...
that's in the store and what's more it is also showing up and universal search box?
What's new though is that is people engage install your app and review and
...that intelligence from store is now also plugged in tubing
dot com intelligence platform and we can start showing app results as hero
answers and bing dot com not just
in-store or in the universal search box but on bing dot com in the browser.
So, that's another canvas where people can find explore
...out so that's great stuff.
Naturally the store listings have a web equivalent
and those web equivalence are index and crawl...the surges...a search engines
that large including bang google and all the other guys.
What's great with universals store there's
...one listing for your up and no more
that bifurcation of sco ranking our between the different
stores the distract from you ranking as well as you can.
However, that's really great if people kind of
know your app name already order searching...a category where you app
...kind of a incumbent leader and category leader.
But, as we said people search differently what they really want to do in a
more natural ways to search for content and things to do.
As it turns out today's app model is kind of broken for that search behavior
there really is an app for everything and people have to go in to the app to kind of
discovered content they want.
...the actions that they want to
...the and often is kind of like a trial-and-error process you need to open up
and app see if the content that you want is...see if you can do what you one where that watch that movie read that.
Advancing we think there's a better model...model a better suits the way people search
that more natural way but also a model.
That helps
developers bring their app to the attention of users as the search
...more natural way so that's why when this ten.
Were bringing...application
...action intelligence to...on a and windows...
And, we're going to make it easy for
developers like yourself to participate in that new canvas.
By allowing to-you standardize markup.
To make the content available to the search engine.
We're going to allow you to improve your app discovery
...discover ability by using applicants app links
...org will allow you to show your app in search results an apple fight
So, that when people find content they can open it
in your immersive experience.
On their windows device.
And, to find actions and to under bring it in understanding to bing...
we're going to allow you to...page with schema dot org and use the
schema that...vocabulary to make those actions known to us.
Now let's see how we're going to do this.
Click.
So, app links the first.
What are the
...there you go so when it comes app...it's really
quite simple protocol if you think about it at length take the known concept the url?
And, creates a relationship with the you awry.
That allows us to launch the app.
This is great because this url is kind of a known concept easy-to-understand that relationships easy to create
but...especially...is that you can published
is url share it link to it from other websites link to it from app to app.
And, we're going to index those relationships and bing and are already being building one of the biggest app linking
in the...in the industry today?
Now what's important is the...in which you can enable this.
It only involves three things one you
marked up the publish url with app links that art metadata.
Second you register a protocol hammer free app so that you app can be
opened by using protocol invocation and finally you
handle the your I activation event in your app.
To kind of guide the user to the content that we've just shown in the search results.
...marking...probably
...pretty straightforward app links really has only simple couple of meta
properties that you can add to your web page the corresponds with your app content.
...show you an example here.
Where we're doing this for a universal windows
up you see there's only a couple of handful of properties that you need to add
a url that point studio ride that you want to open in the app?
The app id which corresponds to your app store id.
And, app name which is not required but it is useful to kind of how about in
their as disambiguation and finally also not
required but smart to do you can add your package family name so
we can disambiguation if there's multiple protocol handlers for the same protocol you
...to...being what understanding create that relationship with your out?
When you've done that you need to registered protocol handler and
luckily that's super easy to do as well with store apps
or really takes is a small extension to your app is
a application manifests and the similar to this here's an example
where I'm adding a handler for the can...scheme?
In visual studio...easier if you open a visual studio and you go
a open your deployment package basically go to declarations tap.
Select protocol from the available declarations and fill out the right metadata.
You know, and, the first-time really when you when you do this and you press
a five just debug app at that point your app is already
registered locally so every time somebody installs...the same thing and you can do.
Windows are something...can...so...on and...
You can start the app from right there but just arnie app is not going to be enough right because
you want us to open the app...the same location that.
Was the location of the content corresponds to
...corresponding weapons.
So, finally what you need to do you handle your I activation again
...pretty a trivial to do.
Basically all it takes in your in your
app to override the on activated event handler.
And, then inspect the arguments to see what the activation...and this cases the protocol.
At that point basically you can look and inspect the arguments to see what the incoming
...request was and then you can navigate to
...view in your app.
And, your service might look slightly differently but it's very easy to do.
...debugging tip when you...a debugging this on activated handler.
Instead of just pressing...debug your app obviously you need to make sure you...open the
...gets activated that way so...quick to.
Even go into your options.
And, go to the start action section and
...do...lawns with debug my code when it starts.
Then press f five now launcher app that say from windows are with the...right
...you wanted to start.
And, at that point...will...to that app and you can have your break front right in there.
Yep, you can try this out ...to this very cool.
Now what's also great and these guys are going to talk about this
even more detail there's a session later today seven-six five
where they're talking about not specifically about app linking for search but app linking to create a web
of apps how apps can link to each other so some of that debugging
ted's and some of these things that you can do there will be presented in much more detail.
We so that people like to search for content...that
...can performance it's...most natural way we know that people search
for people places things entities and...want to do something with it.
So, how can we make bing smart enough and
...on a through bing?
To expose.
Actions that are app can performing content.
...we said we're going to use...arc markup to make that happen.
But, first before we look at the answer let's look at the questions...somebody might be saying listen to
...line is a kind of scary
...story so I want to listen to that before I play that to might kids...way
to the airport's something like that and clearly we have an action here listen action.
...entity core line which in this case is a book are in fact it's,
you know, and, audiobook that I want to listen to.
So, when you schemer...and if you haven't heard about schemer
org it's really a standardized way?
That can be used up to...but there's also a market for
...to basically bring structured data to the web.
And, it was really focused on describing entities such as books such as movies
such as people places and organizations
but they also understood that people want to do things with those entity and twenty fourteen.
They added the action vocabulary to schema...and that's
what I'm going to leverage because it allows us to connect potential actions to entities.
And, it allows us to specify entry points for those
action.
...actions and that includes apps.
Web pages so on so forth.
So, let's look at an example.
Stay with the core line example.
We need to...pages...can...with app links that...that's no problem.
Register protocol...for the app and handley
...activation inside the app and the good news is the first the things we've
already done right so we don't have to do that again so let's look at what that mark-up looks like.
Now I'm going to stick with the
...an example and here's some schemer of mark-up...you can see this is kind of
sm I've compact that into...ld but it could be microformats
...as well and...already describes.
The entity...tells me the type book.
...an additional type is actually in...
The author...isdn number for unique identification
...clearly tells you about all this page is
about the entity caroline which is...but that doesn't mean a lot and I
want to do something with that entity so let's look at what.
Example would be.
We added potential action so this case we use the potential action
attribute to added an action type the typist play action.
You can specify targets for...play action.
One target could just be the web url itself or you might be able to
play the audiobook through the web browser or maybe even listen to sampler something like that but the order is
an entry point that uses a similar way of invocation as app links
does so url template kind of maps to app links url.
And, it shows you the url template basically scheme audible and,
the path that leads to that particular book inside the audible
app we specified that is a software application and the id is the...
...is audible operating system...this cases windows phone eight-point one
...you get the picture we've now successfully connected
the entity...potential action and bing causes information
...to the intelligence platform now this is really
the best way of telling us and letting us know about mapping entities to actions.
That doesn't mean that we do not understand
without it but the more you can give us that accurate information the better we will
...pinpointing the exact relationship between entities and
actions we try to infer a lot of things and...pretty good at infer
...entities...out of unstructured data but adding diskette
structured data really increases your chances of being a candidate for
...action answer in...
Now that's all good maybe I can see quickly
...in here.
We're in the process of
role in working on this and rowing this out and we have a prototype.
For the...cologne.
Will never make it is a hand model?
So, let's...big search arlen there you go so now we have
...entity.
And, we have an app that can perform the action that the user...so let's see what that looks like.
You go.
So, there you see just by have any action...entity and
not even having to call of the app name in this case we were able to launch the
audible lab and I want to thank the audible folks the kind of help is build-out this prototype.
Now a couple take away this.
Is a really great...to start now both...app links and schemer
...because we are ready actively...the web
...extracting that information ahead of windows ten launch?
The action answer as you just saw the example for audible.
Will come along with windows stand?
Okay, gotcha sorry.
Yeah, so, we want to start now.
The action answer will come in certain segments we will started our role in
...out books movies music and we keep expanding on that as windows time progresses.
And, the time to get an edge there's no pun intended lights of the name
...yesterday the time to get an edges now so if you on board
...schemer arc now your chances are much higher of participating in
...can canvas early on in that windows...cycle.
With that I want to point out a couple of quick tools to get
...help you get stuff done first of all webmaster tools not
...is out just because I own
the webmaster experiences but webmaster tools really is the free service that allows you to kind
of monitor how we crawl and index your pages and gives you data back
...free service all it requires is a microsoft account to sign up but that way you can even submit
urls so on so forth and finally just to make a little easier to get started...app links
...published a...test app that allows you to extract
...links...see if I can just switch.
Let me show you how this works.
...again,...put...behind an account.
Yeah, so, quickly lap links markup tester what
...do some lightweight validation but it shows you if we can extract successfully the
...markup on your page.
Prepared.
A little website that contains.
Several examples.
Let's duty example.
City example that...hat.
Right so here.
You cannot see this one.
...my apologies,
yeah, so, I went to aka dot microsoft whack app...
...could entity url here?
...as soon as a fetched url.
We'll see what we can extract obviously this
...task mark-up you wouldn't have all these things in there but here you can
...were able to extract windows eight mark-up windows phone market windows universal market from this particular
...but also ios...because that worked on those platforms
...and we have some lightweight validation that tells you ...might be a typo and what
...specified in terms of the in terms of the platform?
so, very easy to quickly get a look if you want to see what apologies.
...just quickly see what that looks like on the published page.
So, basically.
I exerted might incredible web developer skills to create at the same
...web corresponding web page to the whole...
And, if you look into the source.
You see this kind of.
App links that art mark-up.
...re just for example, but, you can see this works...many device platforms.
Very stream a simple to...great for users now we can link your apps
or search results and entities to action's.
All right without what bring andrew back-up.
And, talk about our call-to-action.
Thank you vincent that's great so basically it's just some simple markups you can make and now
you're apps much more discoverable and just point users specifically deeply inside yet to
...that he wants exactly and the good thing is it's not proprietary so those are
open standards that we can use everywhere on different device types and we brain windows
...into this in a big way awesome applicable orig
signal org great so...thanks again for joining us today I believe
...link like to leave you with is there but being dot com if you go in
there you'll find all of the services the api isn't tools we have been exploring
today and we also released...solutions website for go-to being dot com
...solutions you find the overall being solutions not only that tech ones but also
all the business solutions we can provide you directly to check that as well ...
then if you go to...being...common click on the search api or just go directly to the link you
can see here in the second bullet in this light you can get more information...search api sign up you
...just explore you some exploring lots of different parameters of the api
all the documentation is in there as well and finally some people they really get interested in the
translation thing I just really scratch the surface with...really quick demo you can explore more
...microsoft translator hub website that's hub dot microsoft translator
dot com vincent...the call selection for z at lincoln that discover stuff,
yeah, so, thank you...and participating incur...and especially action,
action answer...now we're working on crawling the web
...creating those relationships enable the applicant...enable schemer
...protocol handling and your activation we did this for your app actually I major
do this and what it took us five minutes to actually...to make this happen and
...entity centric pages that are about entities people places things with that
...mark-up and, finally...the free
being tools that we have use the api is use the webmaster tools to stay
up-to-date about how we crawl and index your website
...use a little things like the app links a markup tester and we will keep expanding
that set of capabilities for developers overcoming months?
With that.
Yeah, that's great so we do have also these channel for you to provide feedback which is
...microsoft is lash being that feedback we are opening this website for all
...tell us what is the direction we should take moving
...api stools and services so-if you-can drop as a comment in there you can check
...contribution in their and...on your suggestions as well that would be great like lisa
...or developer community and be able now to just...steer...api and tools
the right direction and we also have a both in the third-floor...finishes I think...
and today so there's always someone there just go-there talk to us explore more demos
of a bunch of other things to show like the bing developer assistant plug-in so
visual studio couple of other things in...as well so please...to third-floor will be great...been there.
Perfect and we hope you like the session please evaluators now
...small but the lead group here today so please leave your
feedback we appreciate your coming very much and enjoy the rest
...and...safe trip home if you're driving home today or...weekend thank you thank you